clarkcountynv.gov 2019-08-29

# Privacy Policy

---  
  
Clark County takes your privacy seriously and complies with all applicable privacy laws. At the same time, we are committed to providing access to public information as required by law. This policy addresses collection, use and protection of information that may be obtained through use of our website. The information presented here is not meant to be a contract of any type, either express or implied, and should not be treated as such by site visitors. The information in this statement and/or the policies described here may change at any time, without prior notice to any visitor. This policy does not describe information collection policies on other sites, including those linked to or from Clark County.

This notice covers the following topics: 

  * Section A. Information Collected and How it is Used

  * Section B. Personal Information and Choice

  * Section C. Children's Privacy Protection

  * Section D. Public Access to Information

  * Section E. Third-Party Links

  * Section F. Use of Cookies

  * Section G. Security

  * Section H. Electronic Commerce

  * Section I. Health Care Information

  * Section J. Intellectual Property

  * Section K. Contact Information 

  * Section L. Google Analytics Privacy Policy

Contact us if you have any questions concerning this privacy statement at [webmaster@ClarkCountyNV.gov](mailto:webmaster@ClarkCountyNV.gov)  

******Section A. Information Collected and How it is Used**  
  
**Information collected if you only browse this site.** PRIVACY DISCLAIMER:  For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes only the visitor’s domain name. We collect the Internet Protocol (IP) address of visitors to our Web page and the E-mail addresses of those who communicated with us via the E-mail.  Aggregate information on what pages visitors access and information volunteered in the survey information and/or site registrations is collected and used only for internal review to improve the content of our Web page.

The information we collect and store is as follows:

  1. The Internet Protocol (IP) address and the apparent Fully Qualified Domain Name ("Domain Name") used. The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the IP address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (e.g. xcompany.com or yourschool.edu) or of your computer if your computer has a domain name assigned directly to it. Generally, the County only determines visitor domain names if a security issue is suspected. Unless you have directly registered a domain name, this information will not provide the County with your name and/or address; 

  2. The type of browser and operating system you used; 

  3. The date and time you visited this site; 

  4. The web pages or services you accessed at this site; and 

  5. The website you visited prior to coming to this website. 

**What we collect if you volunteer information.**

If during your visit to our website you subscribe to notifications, participate in a survey, send an email, perform some other transaction on-line or by electing to personalize your page and use it as a customized website, additional information may be gathered and used in aggregate for statistical purposes. This may include, but is not limited to:

  1. The email address, and contents of email, for those who communicate with us via email. 

  2. Information volunteered in response to a survey. 

  3. Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose. 

  4. Information volunteered by participating in an on-line transaction with the County. 

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.

We use your email address to respond to you. Survey information is used for the purpose identified by the survey. Information from other on-line forms is used only for conducting County business related to the on-line form.

Information provided for a transaction is used only for the purpose of completing and recording the transaction. Information requested will be no more specific than if a visitor were engaging in the transaction by other means, including by telephone or in-person while visiting a County facility. In all cases, the County strives to collect the minimum information necessary to comply with applicable laws or provide the service requested.  

************************Section B. Personal Information and Choice********  
  
You may choose whether to provide personal information on-line.

"Personal information" is information about a person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us email, subscribing to notifications, participating in a survey, completing an on-line form, or engaging in an on-line transaction. You may choose not to contact us by email, participate in a survey, provide personal information using an on-line form, or engage in an electronic transaction.

However, some information and services available through this site may require us to be able to identify visitors. At any time, while accessing our site, any user, while on-line, may decline participation in any activity that asks for information. Your choice to opt out will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature on the site. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse, read, or download general information provided on the site.

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is treated like any other information provided to the County, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the person identified in the Contact Information Section of this statement.

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children on-line or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.  

**********Section C. Children's Privacy Protection**  
  
Protecting children's privacy on-line is extremely important. Clark County respects national and international laws, including the Children's On-line Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), which applies in the United States.  

******Section D. Public Access to Information**  
  
Nevada Revised Statute 239.010 states that, “All public books and public records of a governmental entity, the contents of which are not otherwise declared by law to be confidential, must be open at all times during office hours to inspection by any person …” “Public records” are regarded as those records which we generate or receive and then maintain in order to conduct business. Some confidential personal identifiers, such as Social Security numbers and date of birth, are not available on-line, for privacy protection. Questions concerning what specific information is available will be addressed by the individual departments maintaining the data. Check the appropriate departmental web pages for details.

Any data mining effort that impairs access to our website or negatively impacts our network infrastructure is prohibited. For example, techniques using site crawlers and spiders cannot degrade access to our website or impact the performance of our servers. See the Security Section G for more details.  

******Section E. Third-Party Links and Disclaimers**  
  
The County’s website has many links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the County’s website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. Visitors linking to another site are encouraged to examine the privacy policy of that site.

Neither the County, department, officer, or employee of the County warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his/her own risk.  

******Section F. Use of Cookies**  
  
Clark County generally, does not use "persistent cookies." Cookies are text files, or entries in larger files, utilized to distinguish between visitors to a website, and to track information during multiple visits to a website. The County uses "temporary cookies" on some parts of its site, and such temporary cookies expire upon termination of the browsing session. Persistent cookies, as an example, may be used to remember the user login.

The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet websites. Most Internet web browsers may be customized to reject cookies, to only accept or reject cookies by user intervention, or to delete cookies. Rejecting and/or removing cookies, however, may lead to loss of functionality.  

************Section G. Security****  
  
Clark County, as developer and manager of its website, has taken a number of steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information that is maintained in its computer systems. Security measures have been integrated into the entire web environment and are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, ensure the integrity of information that is transmitted between users of government applications and the County, and to provide reasonable protection of private information that is in our possession. The transmission of registration IDs, passwords, and payment information to this website is encrypted. For security purposes, to make sure this service remains available to all users, and to meet the needs of our users, Clark County uses special software programs for monitoring and auditing network traffic to measure the level of demand and topics of interest to help us improve our site for users and to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to this government computer system. By accessing this system, users expressly consent to these monitoring activities. Clark County also uses industry-standard software tools to control access to specific applications and services and to protect data that is transmitted electronically between users and the County. These programs help us identify someone attempting to gain unauthorized access to this website. If security monitoring reveals possible evidence of criminal activity, information pertaining to such activity may be provided to law enforcement officials. Unauthorized attempts to upload information and/or change information on the Clark County website or its composite websites are strictly prohibited and are subject to prosecution under the federal Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.  

******Section H. Electronic Commerce**  
  
Increasingly, you have the option to do business with the County over the Web including making electronic payments for goods and services. Such transactions are allowed only under tightly controlled circumstances, where there are appropriate technological and other safeguards in place to protect financial and other sensitive data.

The County properly secures the transmission of information that is exempt from public disclosure with encryption, which includes financial information as defined by Nevada Revised Statutes.  The County does not disclose credit card or other personally identifiable financial information other than as necessary to complete a credit card or other financial transaction, unless explicit permission from the applicable user is obtained, or when compelled by law.

The design of the electronic commerce systems supported on the County's website is such that financial data remains primarily with financial institutions. Wherever possible, financial information is not seen or collected by the County itself. Instead, designated financial institutions route the data, transfer the funds and confirm payment to both you and the County. In addition, measures including but not limited to encryption are used to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of your financial information.

The provision of this information shall not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail-proof, the security of private information as defined by NRS 603A.  

******Section I. Health Care Information**  
  
Any agency providing personally identifiable health care information via the County’s web site is required to certify that its health care data handling and security procedures are in compliance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 ("HIPAA") and the County’s HIPPA and security policies. If such data and security services are provided to such agency(ies) by a third-party provider, the agency(ies) shall be responsible for such third party's compliance with HIPAA.  

******Section J. Intellectual Property**  
  
The content of Clark County's web pages is copyrighted, and may contain some third-party images/graphics that are used with permission. Users are notified, therefore, that one should presume the need to obtain permission from the copyright holder before reproducing or otherwise using images/graphics from this website.  Please send an email to [webmaster@ClarkCountyNV.gov](mailto:webmaster@ClarkCountyNV.gov) if you have questions regarding the use or reproduction of specific images/graphics from this site.  

******Section K. Contact Information**  
  
If you have any questions or concerns about Clark County's use of your information or about this Privacy Statement, please send an email to [webmaster@ClarkCountyNV.gov](mailto:webmaster@ClarkCountyNV.gov) and note "Privacy" in the subject line.  

**

**Section L. Google Analytics Privacy Policy**

**  
  
The Clark County website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google").  Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Google's use of this data is governed by the Google Analytics Terms of Service (http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) and Privacy Policy ([http://www.google.com/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/privacy.html)).  You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
